Kate Bonner

+1•757•771•4472 | katebonner277@gmail.com | katebonner.github.io/portfolio | github.com/katebonner | www.linkedin.com/in/kate-bonner

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with a bachelor's degree in physics, a master's degree in design and technology, and professional experience in cybersecurity. Passionate about the poetic interplay between design and development. Strengths in self-directed learning, creativity in designing solutions, and tenacity in bringing those solutions to fruition.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, SQL, React, MongoDB, ORM, Express.js

Design: Adobe Creative Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, After Effects, Premiere, InDesign), Blender, Cinema 4D, Unity

Language: Native English (level C2), Advanced French (level C1)

Miscellaneous: Network Infrastructure Architecture, Network Security, Oil Painting

PROJECTS

DataBae | GitHub: https://github.com/Bprendaj/databae | Deployed Application: https://warm-castle-61727.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: This project, following the MVC paradigm in its architectural structure, is a chat app, where developers can chat publicly and anonymously after creating a user account.
- Responsibilities: Leveraged bcrypt and express-session node packages for user authentication (sign up, login, and logout functionality), attached a socket.io server to an express server to create the public chat feature, deployed the application to Heroku, designed the UI, created the index, home, dashboard, chat, and API routes, built the user model through sequelize, and established the connection to the JAWSDB and local MySQL database.
- Technologies: sequelize, connect-session-sequelize, mysql2, dotenv, express.js, express-session, handlebars.js, express-handlebars, node.bcrypt.js, and socket.io

Safe Walk | GitHub: https://github.com/katebonner/safe-walk | Deployed Application: https://katebonner.github.io/safe-walk/

- Summary: This project leverage the Google Maps API and the CrimeoMeter API to overlay a heat map of recent assault and robbery location data within 10 miles of the user's position. This map is bolstered with directions to a desired destination input by the user.
- Responsibilities: Leveraged the Google Maps API to generate the base map, generated a Map ID to which I assigned a design on the Google Maps Platform for map styling, plotted a heat map visualization layer given data fetched from the CrimeoMeter API, designed the UI, and initialized the user's starting point from their device's geolocation data.
- Technologies: Google Maps Platform, CrimoMeter, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Darktrace | Cyber Technologist (Sales + Solutions Engineer)

Jul 2021 - Present • New York City Metropolitan Area

- Client-focused role that provides technical and cyber defense expertise in pre-sale and post-sale accounts
- Acted as the technical touch point between clients, partners, and the software engineering and operations team
- During the pre-sale cycle, architected and delivered proof of value trials to demonstrate the efficacy of the Darktrace software
- During the post-sale cycle, architected full deployments and custom integrations for the client's environment
- Served as 1 of 6 'Darktrace for Endpoint' Product Specialists in the Americas
- Named the Top New Cyber Technologist of 2022 in North, South, and Central America for having led 44+ proof of value trials and for having served as the technical lead in closing >2.6M in deals

The Students of Georgetown, Inc. | Creative Director

October 2016 - May 2022 • Washington, DC

- Oversaw the web development, social media presence, photo and video production, and branding services for the Corp, the world's largest entirely student-run non-profit
- Served as the point person for aesthetic direction and technical skills in graphic design and animation

EDUCATION

Columbia University Engineering Bootcamps | Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

April 2022 - Present

 $Relevant\ Coursework:\ HTML,\ CSS,\ JavaScript,\ Node.js,\ SQL,\ React,\ MongoDB,\ ORM$

The Paris College of Art | Master of Arts

September 2020 - May 2021 • Paris, France • GPA 4.0

Department: Transdisciplinary New Media (design and technology)

Georgetown University | Bachelor of Arts

August 2016 - May 2020 • Washington, DC • GPA 3.7

Major: Physics | Double Minor: French and Art

Relevant Coursework: Mathematical Computational Methods for Physics; Linear Algebra; Special Relativity and Quantum Physics, Intermediate Quantum Mechanics; Animation; Computer Science